Today I am going to make a video on the most awaited topic. All of
you have requested me to
tell you about crypto currency. A lot of questions come and a
lot of people also call me to
know about crypto currency.
What is cryptocurrency? What is boxing
technology? What are bitcoins?
Should I do it or not? Is it legal? It is
visual and I did
not want to make this video so that I could meet you. So I
understood it completely and after that I am making today's video
for you. Today we will talk about
what is crypto currency? What are the
advantages and disadvantages of crypto currency? What
is boxing technology? What is bitcoin? Is it
illegal or legal in India? We will
talk about it. We
can add cryptocurrency to it and will
talk about their life and in the last, whether
you should do this match or not, is it right for you or
not.
Before starting the video, I would like to introduce you.
Your name is During and I am
Chiku. I am a certified financial planner
and have got the play of turmeric done by Vijay so that
you have Anshula.  Easy and you yes
brother because our company has given four lines for
creating verification let's go
back to the video
about cryptocurrency it gets anxious that
only one out of 10 people knows
about cryptocurrency sir they also say that three lakh
who are matching cryptocurrency and I
only one person knows whether cryptocurrency has come
and what are they wasting money on
dating and information on Doordarshan they
also say that those who are investing in bitcoins
you go they don't know
where bitcoin came from where it was acquired
who filled the form they don't
know the details so that's why it's important to know if
you want to invest in this digital currency then it's
important to know the complete truth about it only then invest it is
said that
before investing in any match product do your due
diligence do your research
understand it invest and only water was mixed
so it's important to understand first we go
back a little bit to understand cryptocurrency to
understand currency so now currency
Before this, there was currency, your rupee dollar which we
exchange for goods and services, what used to happen
before that was water
system, water system means I
want potatoes and someone else wants onions, okay, so
I can exchange potatoes and onions, I can exchange
any good thing
or services, if I
give something else in return, so the
exchange continued in Gujjar services, water
system, but this found such a thing that if
I want pulses and the other person has pulses
but he does not want what I have, I do
not want what I have, so what happened,
water system was not effective,
then metal system came, that too did
not have any side effect, then after that there is currency,
we talk about the currency which we
use in rupees, so basically what is currency,
currency, if you look at the note, then it is basically a
message of trust, the Central Government Authority,
our Reserve Bank of India has
issued currency, which we
can buy from Gun Sagar by paying that money, so the
solution to its problem was found, it is basically
images of cost, it is written on it.
If you pick up any rupee note and
look at it, it is written on it, I promise you, pay the
customs office holder or whatever the
note is worth, it is attested by RBI
Governor. Images of festivals, Indian festivals. If
you have any queries regarding
services, then you can take it to currency exchange. So,
if you
understand that if you have to transfer currency from one place to another, so that
you do not have to sit and
you want to transfer an amount in dollars to someone,
then you
can directly transfer it to them in dollars from here, otherwise there will be a
tolerant intermediary like a bank,
you will
deposit it in rupees from here, the bank will convert it in dollars
and then go and deposit it in another account there, so it is called
silent
American, so in that entire process,
if you have to transfer currency to someone, then
you cannot do it directly from here, so now let us understand
what cryptocurrency is.
Cryptocurrency is basically a digital currency, a
digital form of cash which you are transferring
to your  From here you are
transferring your cryptocurrency to the US through a bank.
If you can transfer
it to the US from here, then the
time it takes can be from four seconds to
10 minutes to
transfer it to Karachi, so you
can get it directly. Decentralization is a
function, there is no need for any intermediate.
So the currency we use is called crypto currency, we do
not have control over it, the crypto has
control over it, it is free. The
currency has its own control, it has a
room partition, a center receiver
and the beginning of the box end technology, we
can transfer it. Next we will discuss
what is cryptocurrency technology, so cryptocurrency can be
exchanged, which means
one person can give it to another person without any
government intermediary and central
authority. And if we break it down,
all currency functions mean data
encryption, currency means exchange in video,
so you are exchanging currency in digital form, so
first let's
talk about its advantages, first of all it has advantages  It
is decentralized, there
is no central agency, no function or
intermediary between the two. Second, there are no
geographical boundaries. You can
sit anywhere in the world and exchange
two currencies between clans. Third, there is
limited supply of cryptocurrency.
First, if we talk about Bitcoin from here, then
Bitcoin in the form of that, for that reason, it has
only a tenth million supply. You
can use one teaspoon of chilli. It
is transparent from the company where it came from and where it went.
You can understand and see all this. This data is
completely available. The charges are low today compared
to what a bank charges. For example,
if you want to transfer money from here to the US, then the
charges here are
very low. Lastly, it is very fast. As
I said,
you can transfer a currency, digital currency, Bitcoin, for example, from four to ten minutes. There will be
a2b
advantages and disadvantages, so let's
look at the disadvantages. The first
biggest disadvantage is that
if you make this transaction right now  And
wherever possible, for example, if you
transfer money to someone's bank account,
you should tell them the bank account number, the end of which
is 1234, and you transfer it
through the bank for 1243, then the bank
knows which number is in whose name,
so there are chances of it getting reversed, or
chances of it getting reversed, if you make a mistake and
even after transferring it, it will get reversed.
You have a central authority where
you can say and your
transaction record was defeated, it was done
by mistake, here if you
transfer it to the wrong account, then there is
no record of it on WhatsApp,
basically this amount is gone and cannot be returned, it is a
cryptocurrency tile, just like our
sperm quality, similarly crypto
currency is volatile, so it is important to understand this
before making a move, there
is another disadvantage, all this happens
in digital wallet, meaning if you lose your password, then you
cannot reply to it, so the data gets
lost, 20% of it and lastly, the
development difficulty has not happened and the password is  If it
goes then you do not have any way to delete it
and the disadvantage is also that a lot of
illegal activities are done
because there is no central authority, it is
not regulated, so next we will tell you that
we can transfer crypto currency from one place to another,
that is the technology
which is called box in technology, so we will
divide the boxing into two parts,
blog and civil supply, basically what is it, there is
a lock which is full of information,
inside it there is complete data, inside that box
we select the data, what is the data, for example, if there is a
call center, there is a call receiver, how much is being
transferred, when is it being transferred,
all that data is encrypted, what happened in the block, what will happen
when it completely fails,
then another look will come, then the staff will be fully involved in it,
after that if that also fails then
what will happen, another look will come, so what will happen,
this block is intelligent among themselves, for example, if it is
successful in getting the block, then when the
entries carried forward after it will
go in flames, then it will point back to
Lokman, after meeting there is back to,
then after auto, lock is required, do not change it like this
Changes are happening among themselves and
technology is happening right from the wide as call block, so its data
is available for everyone to see, but the
part is that no one can add or delete data,
no one can notify anything, take the Jatin
box for example, now
if someone wants to go back to the option lotto lottery, suppose
someone deleted it, what will happen, its reference is
closed, then that is not possible, so
that data cannot be deleted, everyone
has it, it cannot be deleted, so when you
see, some west side of Hari block
and hospital are linked
among themselves, so every log will be linked with others,
tight this code options and because it
cannot be deleted, sometimes we will talk about boxes and
dubious mix, about bitcoin, that
bitcoin has been, as I
told you, bitcoin is the type of cryptocurrency, in
this way, 6000 cryptocurrencies which I have
created, like your flat currency, like
rupee, this is dollar, this is Mahal Ravana Dahan, in this
way, behind cryptocurrency, thousand from the
most popular  Bitcoin
came in 228, they brought it, if any attempt failed
then you will get this name in plenty, you can
enter bitcoins and invest, no
one knows who this seven faced is, it is
also being said whether it is alive or not, there is
no information but it was brought,
it is said so if we
look at it, Bitcoin is the most popular currency and the
purpose of cryptocurrency is popular, when you
buy Bitcoin, a
user ID, unique Bitcoin user ID and
password is generated with Bitcoin, apart from this you
can do productions like transferring from one place to
another, if you want to
transfer Bitcoin then you will have to
use unique user ID and password, now comes the
million dollar question whether
cryptocurrency is legal in India, the
answer to this is that it is legal, it is
not mentioned anywhere, currently it is legal, you will
also see the platforms where you
can invest, so we will
talk about those platforms also later, but it is legal
tender, what is these legal tender, like if
you have Rupee, then Rupee is legal tender
You already have a chance to
buy something great in exchange for ₹2, so you can't say
that you should buy Bitcoin, Favorite Day,
because you can buy it through comments on this channel, you can
buy it, I will
share it in the names of some people, you can subscribe to the One India
YouTube channel,
that is the process, the
process is that you have to make a bank transfer to
midnight to do cryptocurrency for the first time, after that you get a
unique user ID and password of Bitcoin, so
you
can do portrait and transfer, now going
forward we will talk about the grand finale for which you were
watching this video,
whether you should reverse Bitcoins in cryptocurrency
or not, so for that
first I would like to
tell you, like I told you the advantages and
disadvantages, I told you everything about what
cryptocurrency is, what is Bitcoin, what is
boxing technology
and what are the advantages or disadvantages, so
as I said one and disadvantages,
quality is okay, so just like there is stock market
volatility, similarly you should not have
quality in cryptocurrency  So let's
talk about Bitcoin, we were talking about
Bitcoin being the largest market,
whose total crypto currency is
sixty-five percent market capitalization.
Now, Bitcoin is the most popular,
if we talk about the price of Bitcoin itself,
in 2017 it was 19000 dollars and
Bitcoin was worth one Bitcoin in the
world dollar. In March 2019, its price was 1526.
Bitcoin has been at 19 for 19 years. Today,
we will talk about January 2022,
its price is 1526.75 per Bitcoin, which means
one Bitcoin is worth 31.50 in Indian currency. So, the
general volatility you are seeing is
quite high and as I said,
if you want to start investing, then there are
many traditional cryptocurrencies
available, so you can invest in Bitcoin, but
first you have to learn about it,
after that, if you understand this, then
interest is important, as it is
important to have balance in your portfolio, as it happens
in our balance side, so for that you need to invest in
some mutual funds.  You have to invest in funds, some will go
in real estate, some will get gold,
some will go in your piece romance,
if you should enter the input command, a beginner, a
small amount can be stored in bitcoin also
but after doing your due diligence, so this is how
you must have liked this video about crypto currency and bitcoin,
if you have used it then please
like it and share it with your friends and family
and this is a reminder to tell some passions, if
you have not yet subscribed to the channel then
subscribe and you will get it
in the next video, Saif take care by the
[music]
ki a
kar do
[music] kar do kar
do